A Guide to the Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Collection, 1922-2015
Shenandoah County Library
Shenandoah County Library
Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Collection, 1922-2015
Shenandoah County Library
2018-0001
16 boxes
Records of the Woodstock Chamber of Commerce. Includes legal documents, financial records, meeting minutes, photographs, scrapbooks, and membership records. The documents encompass the history of the chamber from its founding in 1922 through its reorganization as the Shenandoah County Chamber of Commerce in 2011.
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open to researchers without restrictions. Researchers must register and agree to all copyright laws and archives policies before using the collection. Please contact the Shenandoah County Library before visiting to use this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Shenandoah County Chamber of Commerce, March 2018. Originally stored in the Chamber attic.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial (CC-BY-NC)
Administrative Information
The Woodstock Chamber of Commerce was founded in 1922 by a group of local business leaders who sought to improve the local economy. Over the years the organization was responsible for many projects including the construction of the Woodstock Tower, local parades, town beautification efforts, business initiatives, and festivals. The organization merged with several other local chamber of commerce organizations in 2011 and changed its name to the Shenandoah County Chamber of Commerce.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of approximately 16.5 linear feet of materials.
It contains items related to the Woodstock Chamber of Commerce produced between 1922 and 2015. The majority of the items are from the chamber’s membership and board meetings. These include minutes, financial statements, activity reports, and supporting documents.
The collection also contains the chamber’s membership cards for several years ca. 1990. These contain the names of businesses, individuals, and organizations that were members of the chamber and are sorted by membership type.
There is also a small collection of audio and visual materials related to chamber activities.
Arrangement
The Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Collection is divided into the following five (5) series:
Series I: Documents
Box 1, Staff Room
Box 2, Staff Room
Box 3, Staff Room
Box 4, Staff Room
Box 5, Staff Room
Box 6, Staff Room
Box 7, Staff Room
Series II: Audio Materials
Box 8, Staff Room
Series III: Photographs
Box 9, Staff Room
Box 10, Staff Room
Series IV: Membership Cards
Box 11, Staff Room
Box 12, Staff Room
Box 13, Staff Room
Box 14, Staff Room
Series V: Bound Records
Box 15, Staff Room
Box 16, Staff Room
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography+
Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Collection,1922-2015, Truban Archives, Shenandoah County Library, Edinburg, Virginia.
Contents List
- Series I: Documents
  - (Box 1)
    - Minutes, page 116-117, 1926-1927 Minute Book (Folder 1.1)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents, 1926-1928 (Folder 1.2)
    - Letter concerning charter, November 11 1933 (Folder 1.3)
    - Copies, Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Charter, 1933 (Folder 1.4)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents, 1933-1938 (Folder 1.5)
    - Letter, Franklin D. Roosevelt to Representative A. Willis Robertson Concerning Edinburg CCC Camp, March 26 1938 (Folder 1.6)
    - Documents from page 128-129, Minute Book, 1946-1956 (Folder 1.7)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (1 of 3), 1956-1963 (Folder 1.8)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (2 of 3), 1956-1963 (Folder 1.9)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (3 of 3), 1956-1963 (Folder 1.10)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, 1965-1969 (Folder 1.11)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (1 of 4), 1967-1973 (Folder 1.12)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (2 of 4), 1967-1973 (Folder 1.13)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (3 of 4), 1967-1973 (Folder 1.14)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (4 of 4), 1967-1973 (Folder 1.15)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Annual Meeting Program, January 29 1973 (Folder 1.16)
  - 387580101471257, Staff Room (Box 2)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (1 of 7), 1973-1982 (Folder 2.1)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (2 of 7), 1973-1982 (Folder 2.2)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (3 of 7), 1973-1982 (Folder 2.3)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (4 of 7), 1973-1982 (Folder 2.4)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (5 of 7), 1973-1982 (Folder 2.5)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (6 of 7), 1973-1982 (Folder 2.6)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (7 of 7), 1973-1982 (Folder 2.7)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, 1982 (Folder 2.8)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents, 1980-1981 (Folder 2.9)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (1 of 3), 1983 (Folder 2.10)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (2 of 3), 1983 (Folder 2.11)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (3 of 3), 1983 (Folder 2.12)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, 1983 (Folder 2.13)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Annual Meeting Program, January 27 1986 (Folder 2.14)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Business Directory, 1987 (Folder 2.15)
  - 38758101471265, Staff Room (Box 3)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, February 1987 (Folder 3.1)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, March 1987 (Folder 3.2)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, April 1987 (Folder 3.3)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, May 1987 (Folder 3.4)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, June 1987 (Folder 3.5)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, July 1987 (Folder 3.6)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, August 1987 (Folder 3.7)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, September 1987 (Folder 3.8)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, October 1987 (Folder 3.9)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, November 1987 (Folder 3.10)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Documents and Minutes, December 1987 (Folder 3.11)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (1 of 3), 1988-1990 (Folder 3.12)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (2 of 3), 1988-1990 (Folder 3.13)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (3 of 3), 1988-1990 (Folder 3.14)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce “Court Days” Newsletters and Documents, 1986-1987 (Folder 3.15)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Newspaper Clippings, 1986-1992 (Folder 3.16)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, January 1988 (Folder 3.17)
    - "1987 A Year in Review" Script, January 25 1988 (Folder 3.18)
    - "Images'88," Woodstock Women's Club Preview of Spring and Summer Fashions, 1988 (Folder 3.19)
    - Annual Report, Shenandoah Telephone Company, 1988 (Folder 3.20)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, January 1988 (Folder 3.21)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, February 1988 (Folder 3.22)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, March 1988 (Folder 3.23)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, April 1988 (Folder 3.24)
    - Highway Post Office Bus, April 15 1988 (Folder 3.25)
  - Staff Room (Box 4)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, April 1988 (Folder 4.1)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, May 1988 (Folder 4.2)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, June 1988 (Folder 4.3)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, July 1988 (Folder 4.4)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, August 1988 (Folder 4.5)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, September 1988 (Folder 4.6)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, October 1988 (Folder 4.7)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, November 1988 (Folder 4.8)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, December 1988 (Folder 4.9)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Phone Lists, 1989 (Folder 4.10)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Calendars, 1989 (Folder 4.11)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Membership, 1989 (Folder 4.12)
    - Don Garman Memorial Pamphlet, 1989 (Folder 4.13)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Miscellaneous Documents, 1989 (Folder 4.14)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, January-April 1989 (Folder 4.15)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, April and May 1989 (Folder 4.16)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, June-August 1989 (Folder 4.17)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, September and October 1989 (Folder 4.18)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents, November and December 1989 (Folder 4.19)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (1 of 3), 1989-1992 (Folder 4.20)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (2 of 3), 1989-1992 (Folder 4.21)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (3 of 3), 1989-1992 (Folder 4.22)
  - Staff Room (Box 5)
    - Business Directory and Information Guide, 1990 (Folder 5.1)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Treasurer’s Reports, 1992 (Folder 5.2)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Membership List, 1990 (Folder 5.3)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, January 1990 (Folder 5.4)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, February 1990 (Folder 5.5)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, March 1990 (Folder 5.6)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, April 1990 (Folder 5.7)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, May 1990 (Folder 5.8)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, June 1990 (Folder 5.9)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, July 1990 (Folder 5.10)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, August 1990 (Folder 5.11)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, September 1990 (Folder 5.12)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, October 1990 (Folder 5.13)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, November 1990 (Folder 5.14)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes (1 of 3), 1991-1992 (Folder 5.15)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes (2 of 3), 1991-1992 (Folder 5.16)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes (3 of 3), 1991-1992 (Folder 5.17)
    - Court Days, 1992 (Folder 5.18)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (1 of 5), 1993-1995 (Folder 5.19)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (2 of 5), 1993-1995 (Folder 5.20)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (3 of 5), 1993-1995 (Folder 5.21)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (4 of 5), 1993-1995 (Folder 5.22)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (5 of 5), 1993-1995 (Folder 5.23)
  - Staff Room (Box 6)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce By-Laws, 1999-2011 (Folder 6.1)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes (1 of 3), 2000-2005 (Folder 6.2)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes (2 of 3), 2000-2005 (Folder 6.3)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes (3 of 3), 2000-2005 (Folder 6.4)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Clippings and Documents, 2001-2002 (Folder 6.5)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (1 of 4), 2006-2010 (Folder 6.6)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (2 of 4), 2006-2010 (Folder 6.7)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (3 of 4), 2006-2010 (Folder 6.8)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes and Documents (4 of 4), 2006-2010 (Folder 6.9)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Notes, ca.2010 (Folder 6.10)
    - Virginia Main Street, Main Street Essentials, September 22-23 2010 (Folder 6.11)
    - Community Needs Update, 2010-2013 (Folder 6.12)
  - Staff Room (Box 7)
    - Business Resource Guide, 2011 (Folder 7.1)
    - United Way Day of Caring, 2011 (Folder 7.2)
    - Bands, 2011 (Folder 7.3)
    - Community Link Directory Proposal, 2011 (Folder 7.4)
    - Home for the Holidays, 2011 (Folder 7.5)
    - Autumn Fest, 2011 (Folder 7.6)
    - Membership, 2012 (Folder 7.7)
    - Vintage Woodstock, 2014 (Folder 7.8)
    - Vintage Woodstock, 2015 (Folder 7.9)
    - Court Days Pamphlet, Undated (Folder 7.10)
    - Court Days Brochure, Undated (Folder 7.11)
  - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Newspaper Clippings and Supplements, 1988-1996, Location: Map Case Drawer B, Folder 17 (Folder 1)
  - Map of Shenandoah County and Towns, 1994, Location: Oversize Box 1 (Folder 2)
- Series II: Audio Materials
  - Staff Room (Box 8)
    - AUDIO CASSETTE: January 25, 1955 1987 Annual Banquet, Slide Show Audio, app. 5 mins.
    - AUDIO CASSETTE: Wood. Chamber 89" Banquet Tape
    - AUDIO CASSETTE: November 1990
    - AUDIO CASSETTE: 12/19/90 C of C
    - AUDIO CASSETTE: Banquet 1/21/91
    - AUDIO CASSETTE: 1/91
    - AUDIO CASSETTE: Unlabeled Recording
- Series III: Photographs
  - Staff Room (Box 9)
    - Court Day Photographs, 1988
    - Court Day Photographs, 1990
    - Event at Fairgrounds Photographs, 1990
    - US Post Office Highway Post Office Bus, May 1988
  - 38758101471331, Staff Room (Box 10)
    - Photo Slides "1987" A Year in Review'" Annual Meeting, January 25, 1988
- Series IV: Membership Cards
  - Staff Room (Box 11)
    - 1993 members
    - Cards, unidentified
  - Staff Room (Box 12)
    - Businesses, undated
    - Non-Profits, undated
    - Individuals, undated
    - Out of Town, undated
  - Staff Room (Box 13)
    - Businesses, undated
    - Non-Profits, undated
    - Individuals, undated
    - Out of Town, undated
  - Staff Room (Box 14)
    - Businesses, undated
    - Non-Profits, undated
    - Individuals, undated
    - Out of Town, undated
- Series V: Bound Records
  - Staff Room (Box 15)
    - Scrapbook, Woodstock Chamber of Commerce, 1986-1988
  - Staff Room (Box 16)
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, 1922-1927
    - Woodstock Chamber of Commerce Minutes, 1946-1956
    - Guests, 1998-2010